M/R Matthew Read

OBJECTIVE

I am currently enrolled within the IT Web Programming Course at Nova Scotia Community College and have experience in many programming languages and frameworks that support current IT strategies and methodologies. I am a good communicator who is efficient in developing reports and documents with different types of word processing software. I am interested in a position as a Web Programmer as I feel I fit the qualifications and expectations for such job position.



ADDRESS 340, Brookside St. Glace Bay, N.S. B1A-1M5 Canada



PHONE (902) 304-2892



EMAIL MattRead2016@outlook.com

EXPERIENCE

November 2017 – Present Prep/Counter • McDonald's • Glace Bay

April 2019 – May 2019 WordPress Developer • Sydney Sooners/Varsity Sportswear • Sydney, N.S.

EDUCATION

Nova Scotia Community College, Sydney, N.S.

- Currently studying the IT Web Development program.
- Set to graduate in 2020
- Enrolled in 2018
- Has experience with programming and web development technologies, as well as familiarity with many of the IT software applications that support them on the client-side and server-side.

Glace Bay High School, Glace Bay, N.S.

- Graduated in 2018
- Enrolled in 2015
- Honor Student
- Received Highest Distinction award in 2015-2016 school year.

COMMUNICATION

I consider myself to be an intelligent, clearly spoken communicator who can convey their thoughts and opinions in a productive and professional matter. I can apply my communication skills well through writing as I excel in developing reports and documents through word processing suites such as Microsoft Word. I work well within groups alongside other individuals and use proper problem-solving methods to ensure that a specific task can be completed within a specified amount of time.

SKILLS

- HTML and CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery, SASS, XML, React.js, and Node.js
- PHP/Laravel
- Pvthon
- Java, C, and Visual Basic Programming



- **SQL Database Programming**
- Configuring Linux and Windows Based Web Servers for Web Application Development and Testing
- Project Management
- WordPress
- Understanding of the Systems Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Web Design Concepts (ie. Wireframing, Site Mapping, UI/UX, Design Documentation)
- Microsoft Office Software Word, Access, Project